# Nicolas Karayakaylar

Software Developer and Writer



## **Programming**

- > Python
- > C#
- > C++
- > Java

### **Web Dev**

- > Elixir
- > JavaScript
- > HTML
- > SCSS

## **Engines**

- > Unity
- > Unreal
- > GameMaker Studio 2
- > Ren'Py

## Writing

- > Tutorials
- > Plays
- > Visual Novels
- > Role-Playing Games
- > Comedy

#### **Awards**

- > Eagle Scout
- > Winner of Traverse City Young Playwrights' Festival
- > National Merit Semifinalist
- > Rennselaer Medalist

#### **Websites**

> Github: github.com/nicolassims

## **Profile**

I am a recent college graduate currently working in the computer science field, where I am leveraging my abilities as a skilled programmer and writer. I am courteous, curious, and take pride in my work. I have worked internationally, and love to travel. Personal and professional references are available upon request.

## **Education**

Northeastern University | Boston, MA

Khoury College of Computer Sciences | May 2021

**BS in Computer Science and Game Development** 

Graduated with Honors | Dean's List, 4 years

**Relevant Courses:** Web Development, Computer Systems, Object-Oriented Design, Networks and Distributed Systems, Algorithms and Data, Software Development

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Junior Game Developer**

Super League Gaming | Santa Monica, CA | Dec 2021 - Present

- > Creating new game modes/products for InPvP Bedrock Minecraft servers.
- > Providing service to modes and products approved by partner, Microsoft.
- > Working with management to develop backend services and frontend maps.
- > Receiving, interpreting, and implementing feature specifications.

#### Lead Developer

Freudian Creations | Remote | Sept 2017 - Present

- > Managing a team of 7+ artists to deliver assets on time.
- > Posting bi-weekly developer blogs, updating audience on progress.
- > Growing and maintaining audience of ~300 interested followers.
- > Programming and implementing cutscenes for an original cutscene engine.

#### **Extended Realities Application Developer**

Biogen | Cambridge, MA | July 2019 - Dec 2019

- > Designed interactive models of human biosystems for VR environments.
- > Used the Unity engine to program applications for CAVE systems.
- > Created applications for Oculus and HTC headsets.
- > Adapted platform-specific code for compatibility with other platforms.

#### **Digital Alternate Reality Game Developer and Writer**

Extra Ludic | Boston, MA | Oct 2017 - May 2018

- > Expanded option trees to accommodate a wide range of player input.
- > Wrote dialogue and room descriptions for virtual labyrinths and NPCs.
- > Designed location-dependent gameplay for use in an ARG.
- > Implemented aforementioned gameplay using ARIS engine.